<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Scientific Software Days</title><link href="http://scisoftdays.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://scisoftdays.org/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://scisoftdays.org/</id><updated>2013-10-22T13:17:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Announcing XSEDE Sponsorship</title><link href="http://scisoftdays.org/news/2013/10/22/announcing-xsede-sponsorship/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-22T13:17:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy R. Terrel &lt;andy.terrel@gmail.com&gt;</name></author><id>tag:scisoftdays.org,2013-10-22:news/2013/10/22/announcing-xsede-sponsorship/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's my pleasure to announce that XSEDE has become an official sponsor for
SciSoftDays2013!  XSEDE is a leader in providing resources for scientific
computing and is support SciSoftDays in it's mission of training scientists in
the best software practices in our field.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please keep posted as we plan on announcing our call for proposals and keynotes
soon.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Scientific Software Days 2013 Details</title><link href="http://scisoftdays.org/news/2013/09/25/scientific-software-days-2013-details/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-25T14:17:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy R. Terrel &lt;andy.terrel@gmail.com&gt;</name></author><id>tag:scisoftdays.org,2013-09-25:news/2013/09/25/scientific-software-days-2013-details/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've revamped the webpage and are getting started on SSD2013! So mark
your calendars for Dec. 16 and 17. To follow along book mark the
&lt;a href="http://scisoftdays.org/pages/2013_details.html"&gt;SSD2013 details page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we have already lined up two amazing speakers, Neil Chue
Hong and James Howison.  Both these gentlemen have made their name
analyzing and promoting sustainable scientific software.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few other changes are taking place.  We plan on going back to the
two day format.  With one day for interesting tutorials and the second
for our speaker series. Additionally with the success of last year, we
are getting a bigger room!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look forward to seeing you there.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SSD2012 schedule up</title><link href="http://scisoftdays.org/news/2012/11/28/ssd2012-schedule-up/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-28T14:28:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Andy R. Terrel &lt;andy.terrel@gmail.com&gt;</name></author><id>tag:scisoftdays.org,2012-11-28:news/2012/11/28/ssd2012-schedule-up/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to announce the 2012 Scientific Software Days &lt;a href="/pages/2012_details.html#schedule"&gt;schedule&lt;/a&gt; is official
posted.  This year we have a range of core technology talks, open science
talks, and software in applications talks.  In what may be a first for SSD, we
have two speakers from medical schools, a growing segment in scientific
software user base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon, we will have logistics information up soon for all to see.  But if
you have any questions feel free to email us at softwareday@tacc.utexas.edu.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Announcing Scientific Software Days 2012</title><link href="http://scisoftdays.org/news/2012/09/25/announcing-scientific-software-days-2012/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-25T14:17:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Andy R. Terrel &lt;andy.terrel@gmail.com&gt;</name></author><id>tag:scisoftdays.org,2012-09-25:news/2012/09/25/announcing-scientific-software-days-2012/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CALL FOR PARTICIPATION: &lt;a href="http://scisoftdays.org/pages/2012_details.html"&gt;6th ANNUAL SCIENTIFIC SOFTWARE DAYS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Deadline for Proposals: Nov 1, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACES 2.402&lt;br /&gt;
University of Texas at Austin&lt;br /&gt;
Austin TX&lt;br /&gt;
December 17, 2012&lt;br /&gt;
9 AM -- 5 PM  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists use software for their research. Some of them also develop
computational software as part of their research. Scientific Software
Days is an ongoing meeting of users and producers of scientific
software, with presentations by scientific software tool makers and
the users of their tools. The objective is to build cross-disciplinary
community and skills in the diverse set of users and developers of
scientific software, both academic and industrial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most groups that use supercomputing cope with their scientific
software environment in isolation, not always
relying on prepackaged “canned” solutions. Many successful lines of
research and development are achieved, but many times less than
optimal paths are taken, simply because computing is done by people
stretched between computational skills and skills in the relevant
science and engineering specialties. Available tools and methods are
not always known to the people who need them, and time pressure makes
it hard to make the best use of the tools available. Support staff at
supercomputing centers is stretched and is best at responding to
specific issues rather than offering broad support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We seek to build a community to address these needs. The Scientific
Software Days at UT Austin is intended to nucleate that community. If
you are involved in any end use or development of scientific software,
you can benefit from and contribute to this goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is, therefore, a somewhat unusual call for presentations. Ideal
presentations for Scientific Software Days are of two types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;presentations of generic tools that can be used in scientific
software development and deployment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;presentations of specific work, focusing on experience in
developing scientific software, workflows, and tool chains. We are
especially seeking presentations of the second type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would appreciate a brief introduction to your work intended for a
general scientific audience, and then a focus on your workflow or any
particular aspect of it that presented particular challenges or
required original solutions. The target audience will be a broad
selection of the scientific and engineering communities with a
particular interest in supercomputing. Let’s get to know each other
and learn from one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="http://scisoftdays.org/pages/2012_details.html"&gt;Conference Details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/viewform?formkey=dHVQWmYtb2ZCeGdyckNVSThKenpPRVE6MQ"&gt;Talk Submission&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</summary></entry></feed>